Guide to the James Omura personal archive M2294
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 9. Research Materials, 1930-1994
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Kido, Saburo, 1944 (Box 47, Folder 19)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Kikuchi, Charles, 1941 (Box 47, Folder 20-21)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Kikuchi, Charles, 1943 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Koshiyama, Mits (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Krammer, Arnold, 1953 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Kurihara, J. Y. (Joe), 1943 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Larson, T. A., 1978 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Liddell, B. H, 1970 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Lunt, Carroll (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Makoto, Sugawara (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Manchester, William, 1973-1974 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Martin, James J., 1978 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Masaoka, Mike, 1944, 1987 (Box 48, Folder 11-2)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Masuda, Violet, 1974 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Miyamoto, Frank, n.d., 1985 (Box 48, Folder 14-15)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Miyoshi, Nobu M.S.W. (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Murayama, Yuzo, 1982 (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Mydans, Carl (Box 48, Folder 18)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Nagano, Paul M. (Dr.) (Box 48, Folder 19)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Naito, Calvin & Scott, Esther, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 20)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Nash Philip Tajitsu, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 21)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Nelson, Douglas W. (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Niiya, Brian, 1988 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Nitobe, Inazo, 1891 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Notebook Title: “The Role of Social Scientists and Dialectrical” by Peter Suzuki and “Unpublished History of the JACL” by Togo Aka: “8/25/41-5 to 8/25/41-49” (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Notebook Title: “The Role of Social Scientists and Dialectrical” by Peter Suzuki and “Unpublished History of the JACL” by Togo Aka: “Chapter III” “Chapter IV” (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Notebook Title: “The Role of Social Scientists and Dialectrical” by Peter Suzuki and “Unpublished History of the JACL” by Togo Aka: “.. .From an unpublished history of the JACL written by Togo Tanaka in 1944” (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Notebook Title: “The Role of Social Scientists and Dialectrical” by Peter Suzuki and “Unpublished History of the JACL” by Togo Aka: Request for photocopying; Togo Tanaka Report (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Yoneda, Karl G.Social Scientists and Dialectrical” by Peter Suzuki and “Unpublished History of the JACL” by Togo Aka: 9, 13-16, 19, 21-30, 21-28, 28, 36, 47-60, 71, 46-48, 33-37, 55-62 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Notebook Title: “The Role of Social Scientists and Dialectrical” by Peter Suzuki and “Unpublished History of the JACL” by Togo Aka: “Pacific Citizen” (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Notebook Title: “The Role of Social Scientists and Dialectrical” by Peter Suzuki and “Unpublished History of the JACL” by Togo Aka: Request for photocopying; “Chapter III”, “Chapter IV” (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Oka, Naoki, 1928 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Okamura, Raymond Y, 1974, 1981 – 1982, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Okihiro, Gary Y. (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Ozaki, Milton K., 1988 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Patterson, William L. (Editor), 1951 (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Phillips, Cabell (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Robinson, William, 1942 (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Sakoda, James (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Sato, Masayuki (Box 49, Folder 19)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Schonberger, Howard, 1989 (Box 49, Folder 20)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Schweik, Susan, 1989 (Box 49, Folder 21)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Shapiro, Harriet (Box 49, Folder 22)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Shogan, Robert (Box 49, Folder 23)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Spencer, Robert, 1943 (Box 49, Folder 24)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Spickard, Paul R., 1983 (Box 49, Folder 25)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Stearns, Marjorie R., 1937 (Box 49, Folder 26)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Stetson, Conn; Engelman, Rose C.; Fairchild, Byron, 1970 (Box 49, Folder 27)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Sundquist, Eric J., 1988 (Box 49, Folder 28)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Suzuki, Peter T., 1980 – 1981, 1985 – 1986 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Tanaka – Manzanar Addenda, 1943 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Tanaka, Stefan Akio, 1977 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Tateishi, John, 1984 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Tatsuzo, Ishikawa (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Taylor, Paul S., 1942 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Thomas, Dorothy S.; Nishimoto, Richard, 1969 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Thorne, Christopher, 1978 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Tomita, Mary Kimoto, 1939-1947 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Tono, Jack, 1984-1986 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Tsucheda, Nobuya (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Watanabe, George (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Wedemeyer, Albert C. (General), 1958 (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Weglyn, Michi Nishiura, 1992 (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Wesley, Newton K., O.D., M.D, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Whitfield, Willard D, 1942 (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Williams, Robert H., 1990 (Box 50, Folder 17)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Yamane, Tokio (Box 50, Folder 18)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Yasui, M., 1941 (Box 50, Folder 19)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Yasutake, S. Michael, 1977 (Box 50, Folder 20)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Yoneda, Karl G. (Box 50, Folder 21)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 22-28)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings, 1930-1987 (Box 51, Folder 1-21)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings, 1988-1990 (Box 52, Folder 1-18)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings, 1991-1993 (Box 53, Folder 1-19)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings, 1994-1995 (Box 54, Folder 1-6)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings - Karl Bendetsen, John McCloy, 1989 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings - Frank Chin, 1987-1992 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings - Frank Emi, 1988-1993 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings - Alberto Fujimori, bulk (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings - Aiko Herzig, bulk (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings - Gordon Hirabayashi, bulk (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings - William Hohri, bulk (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings - Lawson Inada, 1993 (Box 54, Folder 14)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings - Paul Ito, 1990-1993 (Box 54, Folder 15)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings - Fred Korematsu, bulk (Box 54, Folder 16)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings - George Nozawa, 1988, 1991, 1993 (Box 54, Folder 17)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings - Michi Nishiura Weglyn, 1991-1993 (Box 54, Folder 18)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings - Clippings - Minoru Yasui, 1982-1992 (Box 54, Folder 19)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings - Clifford Uyeda, bulk (Box 54, Folder 20)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings - Books & Authors, 1986-1990 (Box 54, Folder 21)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings - Combat Teams, 1990-1993 (Box 54, Folder 22)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings - Court Cases, 1947, 1983-1992 (Box 54, Folder 23)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings - Fair Play Committee; Redress, 1990-1993 (Box 54, Folder 24)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings - Film & Art, 1984-1992 (Box 54, Folder 25)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings - Films on Japanese American Experience, 1984-1990 (Box 54, Folder 26)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings – Hawaii Herald, Asian Week, Hokubei Mainichi, American Spectator, London Review of Books, 1982-1993 (Box 54, Folder 27)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings - Heroic Support, 1989, 1992, 1994, 1982-1992 (Box 54, Folder 28)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings – Hokubei Mainichi, Asian Week, Hawaii Herald, Pacific Citizen, Spotlight, Rafu, 1990-1994 (Box 54, Folder 29)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings – Hokubei Mainichi, San Francisco Examiner, 1990-1991 (Box 54, Folder 30)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings - Clippings – Insight, Hobubei Mainichi, Asian Family Affair, Hawaii Herald, Kashu Mainichi, Tozai Times, 1990 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings – “Is Japanese America Ignorant of its History?”, et. al, 1983-1992 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings – Intelligence: Heart Mountain, 1940's (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings – Japanese American Citizens League (JACL, 1987-1990 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings – National Coalition for Redress/Reparations (NCRR), 1988-1994 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings – Nissei Education; Manzanar Riot, et al., 1941 – 1943, 1980, 1986, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings – Pearl Harbor Inquiry, 1946 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings – Peruvians, 1984, 1989, 1993, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings – Research Materials in Japanese (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings – Redress, bulk (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings – Resistance, 1940’s, 1980’s, 1990’s (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - Writings & Manuscripts - Clippings - Sports, 1940’s, 1950’s, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 12)
- Series 10. Michi Nishiura Weglyn and Aiko Herzig Yoshinaga Correspondence and Documents
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Materials donated by Michi Nishiura Weglyn and Aiko Herzig Yoshinaga realting to James Omura
  - Correspondence - Aiko Herzig-Yoshinaga and James Omura, 1984-1993 (Box 55, Folder 13)
  - Copies of newspaper articles written by or about James Omura, collected by Aiko Herzig-Yoshinaga, 1940-1990 (Box 55, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence of Michi Weglyn and James Omura, biographical information and memorial articles about James Omura (Box 55, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence of Michi Weglyn and James Omura, 1985-1989 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence of Michi Weglyn and James Omura, and Art Hansen; FOIPA request for documents pertaining to Japanese Citizens League and copy of documents, copies of articles and documents (Box 56, Folder 1-2)
- Series 11. Wayne Omura's Collection of James Omura's Personal Archive
  General
  Note with archive says "material donated by Wayne Omura, youngest son of James Matsumoto Omura
  - Subseries 11.1 Documents
    - Personal documents including high school graduation certificate, birth certificate, social security card, National Liberal Lerague member card for 1947, life insurance policy, discharge of bankrupt (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Various letters, Letter from Amateur Athletic Union of the United States is very fragile; it was cleaned of mold. (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Sports articles written by James Omura (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Omura Landscaping Service - stationery, contract, newspaper clippings (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - The Japan-California daily news - article, Very brittle but available on microform (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Income ledger, 1945; sheet of paper with numbers and with diary entries for Jan 3-4 [no year] (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Tax returns for James Omura and Caryl Omura, 1942-1947 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Letter from Caryl Fumiko, first wife of James Omura, date August 2nd 1946 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence - Casey (Kazushi Matsumoto) and James Omura (Box 56, Folder 11)
      Note from donor says Casey is James' brother.
  - Subseries 11.2 Day Calendars and Journals
    - Day book - income and expenses, 1944-1946 (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - Appointment calendars with many journal style entries, arranged by year, 1966, 1968 (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - Appointment calendars with many journal style entries, arranged by year, 1969-1970 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Appointment calendars with many journal style entries, arranged by year, 1971-1972 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Appointment calendars with many journal style entries, arranged by year, two books for 1973 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Appointment calendars with many journal style entries, arranged by year, 1975-1977 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Small spiral bound memo book with journal entries for May - August 1982; bound journal and a photocopy of the journal, 1981-1983 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Four small 3"x5" spiral bound memo books with journal entries, 1983 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Five small 3"x5" spiral bound memo books with journal entries, 1984 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Four small 3"x5" spiral bound memo books with journal entries, 1985 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Four small 3"x5" spiral bound memo books with journal entries; bound journal for the year, 1986 (Folder 3-4)
    - Three small 3"x5" spiral bound memo books with journal entries [first part of the year is missing], 1987 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Four small 3"x5" spiral bound memo books with journal entries, 1988 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - One small 3"x5" spiral bound memo book with journal entries, April - August 1989; one 4"x6" spiral bound memo book with journal entries, 1989-1990 (Half-box 59, Folder 1)
    - Two 4"x6" spiral bound memo books with journal entries, 1990-1994 (Half-box 59, Folder 2)